rescue.org 2015-06-10

# Respecting Your Privacy - International Rescue Committee privacy policy | International Rescue Committee (IRC)

This Web site is owned and operated by the International Rescue Committee ('the IRC'). We recognize that visitors to our site may be concerned about the information they provide to us, and how we treat that information. This Privacy Policy addresses those concerns.

The IRC uses its best efforts to respect the privacy of its online visitors. At our site, we do not collect personally identifiable information from individuals unless they provide it to us voluntarily and knowingly. This means we do not require you to register or provide information to us in order to view our site. The IRC only gathers personally identifiable information, such as names, addresses, zip/postal codes, e-mail addresses, etc., when voluntarily submitted by a visitor. For example, personally identifiable information may be collected in order to respond to a stated desire to apply for a position, volunteer time to the IRC, make a donation online or sign up for an IRC mailing list. This information is available to the IRC and third-party application service providers involved in the operation of this site. We make an effort to require all third-party application service-providers to hold personal information in strict confidence. While we believe these companies are upstanding and will treat your personal information responsibly, we do not own or control them.

As with most other Internet sites, our Web server automatically recognizes the domain name of each visitor to the site, but not the e-mail address (where possible). This IP address tells us which domain you visited from (e.g. aol.com). We use the information we record to help diagnose problems with our server, and to improve the content of our Web page. The information is not shared with other organizations for commercial purposes.

How do I control how IRC uses my personal information?

Opt-Out

If you supply us with your postal address or e-mail address online you may receive periodic mailings from us with information on our programs and services. If you do not want to receive postal mail and/or e-mail from us in the future, please let us know by sending your request via e-mail to [donorservices@rescue.org](mailto:donorservices@rescue.org?subject=IRC%20privacy%20policy).

The IRC will never rent, trade or sell your e-mail address. However, we may on occasion share your name and postal address with other organizations unless you opt-out. If you would prefer that your name and postal address not be shared with other, simply send us a request via e-mail to [donorservices@rescue.org](mailto:donorservices@rescue.org?subject=IRC%20privacy%20policy).

Exceptions to Opt-Out

The IRC may disclose personal information if compelled by law or a regularity authority.  In addition, we may need to disclose personal information in special cases where we have reason to believe that disclosing this information is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be causing injury or interfering (either intentionally or unintentionally) with IRC’s rights or property, IRC Web site users, or anyone else that could be harmed by such activities.

Is my Credit Card Information Secure?

Protecting your credit card information is of the utmost importance to the IRC.  The IRC’s online donation site has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of information under our control.  We make every effort to insure the secure collection and transmission of sensitive user information, including credit card information, by using SSL (Secure Socket Layer) encryption technology. This method reflects industry standard security protocol and makes it extremely difficult for anyone else to intercept your credit card information.  
If you would prefer to give by mail, please send your check to International Rescue Committee, 122 East 42nd Street, New York, NY 10168. If you would like to make a credit card donation by phone or fax, you may call +1 855 9RESCUE or fax your credit card information to (212) 551-3183.

How Do We Use "Cookies"?

Visitors should be aware that non-personal information and data may be automatically collected by the IRC’s Web site through the use of "cookies." "Cookies" are small text files a Web site can use to recognize repeat visitors, facilitate the visitor’s ongoing access to and use of the site, and allow a site to track usage behavior and compile aggregate data that will allow content improvements.

Cookies are not programs that come onto a visitor’s system and damage files. Generally, cookies work by assigning a unique number to the visitor that has no meaning outside the assigning site. If a visitor does not want information collected through the use of cookies, there is a simple procedure in most browsers that allows the visitor to deny or accept the cookie feature. The IRC uses "cookie" technology only to obtain non-personal information from its online visitors in order to improve visitors’ online experience and facilitate their visit within our site.

What rules apply if I "click" over to another Web site?

In order to provide certain services and materials, our Web site may allow you to “click” over to other Web sites. This Privacy Policy only applies to [www.Rescue.org](http://www.rescue.org/).  This Privacy Policy does not apply to any third party sites. IRC is not responsible for the privacy practices or content of such other Web sites, even if our name and logo appear on the screen.  We recommend that you review the privacy policies on third-party sites before you use any services or programs they offer.

Do we collect information from children ages 13 and under?

The IRC believes every measure of precaution should be taken to protect children online and does not knowingly ask children ages 13 and under for any information.  Visitors 13 and under should ask their parent or legal guardian for assistance when using [www.Rescue.org](http://www.rescue.org/) and should not submit any personally identifiable information to the IRC. 

Do we periodically revise our Privacy Policy?

IRC may revise this Privacy Policy from time to time without advance notice. Accordingly, we recommend that you check for updates to this Privacy Policy on an on-going basis. Changes were last made to this Privacy Policy on June 15, 2009. 

Who do I contact with questions or comments about this Privacy Policy?

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact:

International Rescue Committee  
122 East 42nd Street  
New York , New York  10168-1289

Or e-mail us at [webmaster@rescue.org](mailto:webmaster@theIRC.org)  
By using the IRC’s Web site, you signify your agreement to this Privacy Policy. However, you are under no obligation to disclose any personal information to the IRC if you do not want to. If you are not comfortable with IRC’s uses of your personal information, you may always decide to opt out or decide not to use those Web site services or features that require your personal information.
